a production of
BANDAI VISUAL, TOKYO FM, DENTSU,
TV ASAHI, SAITO ENTERTAINMENT
and OFFICE KITANO
a film by Takeshi Kitano
ZATOICHI
Kid...
Bring us that blind masseur's cane.
We'll pay you if you succeed.
Be careful.
Do it quietly, so he won't hear.
Thanks.
Scram!
Beat it, brat!
Ichi!
Even you...
Fooled by an innocent child!
Even a master is powerless
without his weapon.
REST STOP
Drink up!
What are you doing?
You were the Naruto family's clerk.
Don t you recognize us?
The Naruto family?
I'm the daughter!
What now?
We already paid this month!
You didn't pay today!
Now you have to pay
each time we come by.
- We'll have nothing to live on.
- Stop complaining!
Shut up and pay.
Things weren't this bad
with the Funahachi gang.
The Ginzo gang makes life hell!
Damn you!
This must be quite a sight!
I'm guiding a masseur
who's carrying my vegetables.
Wish I could see that!
You did me a big favor.
Have some tea.
It's hot.
Thank you.
Without your help...
I wouldn't have made it home.
Where will you sleep tonight?
Must be your first time around here.
You're welcome to stay here.
I live alone.
Don't get any ideas.
I don't have any.
- Too hard?
- No, it's just right.
I hate thinking the town is doomed.
Ginzo and Ogi have teamed up.
They're running the town at will.
You really have such crooks?
They bully the farmers around.
And the townspeople, too.
They demand protection money
every day.
At this rate,
the more we work, the poorer we get.
You pay protection money daily?
Before, no...
We used to pay only monthly.
Big difference between
monthly and daily.
Exactly.
Are you alright?
We'll stay here a while.
I'll work as a bodyguard again.
You shouldn't worry about me.
Don't do that kind of work
for my sake.
I'll get an official post again someday.
Stop worrying. You need rest.
Hey, Pops!
Where's gramps?
He's sick in bed.
Won't be coming in today.
You work him too much.
Sorry.
Take better care of him.
The sake is horrible as usual.
Can't get anything better.
Same story for 10 years!
Can you hand this
to that guy over there?
I don't work for you!
What nerve!
Can't get it yourself?
Drink at the counter!
W-w-welcome.
Welcome, my ass!
Where's this month's payment?
Please give me more time.
What a joke!
We don't wait!
I'll work things out.
My regards to your boss.
Your sake is disgusting!
Shut up!
What do you want?
Send a message to your boss...
Skilled ronin
seeks position as bodyguard.
Samurai...
It's late...
The Ginzo boss may not come.
Masterless samurai...
Are you the one?
The one who seeks work
as a bodyguard?
Show me your skills.
That's very good.
Not the cord...
Look at your foot.
Masseur, I’m going to the fields.
Tell me, ma'am...
Is there anything I can do to help?
Thank you for offering.
But I couldn't ask
a sight impaired man to chop wood.
Don't worry. Relax.
Dear...
You returned late last night.
Did something happen?
I found a good job.
Another position as a bodyguard?
I beg you, not for my sake.
I beg you,
please stop taking such jobs.
Don't be silly.
With money, you could be cured.
Tell me...
Did you hire that ronin?
Yes.
We have two problems to take care of.
We must destroy both clans,
the Izutsu and the Funahachi.
Then this post town will be yours, Boss.
Try not to be too rough.
Understood.
Don't worry.
By the way...
Any news about Heihachi's murder?
Some rumors...
They say a geisha killed him.
That's all we know for now.
Another bowl, masseur?
No, thanks.
I'm full. Thank you very much.
Ma'am, when I was chopping wood...
This guy ran around the house.
What was all that about?
The neighbor's son. A certified idiot.
Pay him no mind.
He dreams of being a samurai.
He runs around like that all day.
A samurai!
Well...
I'm going out a while.
For work?
Not exactly.
For this.
What? You're going gambling?
Better to stay away from that.
My nephew...
He's addicted to gambling.
He refuses to work, plays all day.
Don't know...
He dropped out of sight.
For me, it's just a pastime.
Some pastimes can become too serious.
What do you think?
This sword cost me a fortune.
Yes, Mr. Ogi, it's a fine sword.
I'm giving it to Lord Sakai.
He'll be so pleased
that he'll do us business favors.
Of course.
Actually...
Try it out on the first beggar
who comes by.
- Who? Me?
- Yes, you!
Thanks, sir. But you go ahead.
Out of the question!
I won't dirty my kimono!
You do it!
Why not hire a ronin?
Fool!
Hire a ronin just to test a sword?
- Do as I say!
- But...
Someone's coming!
Slay that blind man.
Hurry up!
Scared of a blind man?
My... my sword!
I’m so sorry!
You fool!
Game!
3 and 1, even.
New game!
Any objections?
Ouch!
A blind man?
Sit here, blind man.
I'm a masseur.
Even.
Bets are placed.
Game.
3 and 2, odd.
I’m out of luck.
New game.
Objections?
Odd.
Aren't you betting?
I’ll just watch for now.
Watch? But you're blind.
1 and 1, even.
Boss!
The bodyguard is here.
Place your bets.
Odd.
Even.
Bets are placed.
Game.
4 and 2, even.
Any objections?
Objections?
Is that them?
Yes.
Stop! Please don't!
It's done...
Mr. Ogi's worries are over for now.
Welcome.
Some sake.
Pops...
Can I have more sake, too?
Samurai...
Masseur...
Your cane! I’m so sorry.
What a beautiful cane!
Well, masseur...
You're no ordinary masseur.
I smell blood on you, too.
It's a little cramped in here.
No use drawing swords like that.
Dear...
Did you have to kill again?
Idiot!
It's too early for this racket.
Go home.
Battle time is over.
The masseur didn’t come home last night.
Maybe he got lucky.
OGI
Sir!
I'll take this to Lord Sakai.
Wait.
On your way back...
Treat yourself to something tasty.
Thank you, sir!
Next! Kaneko Heishiro!
Some ronin are very powerful.
Hattori will be the one to face them.
Coward!
Using sticks
isn't the art of combat!
A true samurai
will use his sword!
You, Yamaji Isaburo...
Yes.
And who are you?
Hattori Gennosuke.
I must slay you to regain my honor.
Get your sword!
Kill me, if you want.
I don’t have...
I have never had a sword.
Where is the glory?
In killing an invalid like me?
Using sticks isn't the art of combat!
A true samurai will use his sword!
He's as good as dead.
Not worth killing.
Hurry up!
Why such a rush?
Quiet! Show me what you have.
Isn't that better?
2 and 3, odd.
New game.
Objections?
Place your bets.
What should I bet?
Odd.
Can I join you?
Odd!
Bets are placed.
Game.
4 and 1, odd.
Yeah! Over here!
Masseur...
It's full of fine women.
You look like a winner.
Thanks to this masseur,
I hit the jackpot.
So why not buy a night with us?
Masseur...
should we have a little fun?
I'll talk to the Madam.
I'll find five or six geishas.
I'll take care of it, young master.
Stay here. I'll go.
Ouch! That hurts!
I'm not a bunny.
Don't pull my ears!
No need to get violent!
Don't be naughty!
So much? Impossible!
Ouch! That hurts!
Could I stand a small needle?
No, the smaller the needle...
The bigger the pain!
Very funny! Come over here.
- Have a drink.
- Thank you.
Really funny!
See that, Masseur?
I don't see much.
Osei, ready to dance?
Dance? Great!
Go on, dance!
Miss Okinu...
why did you loosen the strings?
Are you after our money?
And you, Miss Osei...
Aren't you a man?
You don't smell like a woman.
The blind...
They're sensitive to such things.
A hidden dagger?
What's all this about?
Masseur...
You may think I’m lying...
But I will tell you the truth.
Our father...
He was a wealthy rice merchant.
Come and see Cotton.
Don't tell anyone.
Heihachi...
You have endured seven long years.
Heihachi, where is it hidden?
This way.
How many are there?
The Naruto couple, their two children,
three maids and four clerks.
Tashichi, what did you find?
Eight strongboxes of money.
They saved a fortune!
Inosuke, we're set for life!
Get the Kuchinawa boss.
Did you kill everyone in the house?
What about the kids?
They're nowhere to be found.
Fool!
We're out of time. Let's go.
We tracked down Heihachi, the clerk...
What are you doing?
You were the Naruto family's clerk.
Don’t you recognize us?
The Naruto family?
I'm the daughter!
As for the others,
I only know names...
Tell me.
Inosuke and Tashichi.
They also spoke of the Kuchinawa boss.
That's all we know.
And you've searched all these years?
Even.
Wrong again!
I’ll try with my eyes closed.
Like him.
How does he do it
by listening?
I’m so unlucky!
One rolled away!
That's the problem.
Odd.
Even.
I think I got it.
My senses are sharper
with my eyes closed.
OK!
Shinkichi!
You're just sitting
with your eyes closed.
Aren't you betting?
I'm listening.
What?
Sitting up front just to listen?
I have the right to listen.
Are you looking for trouble?
Don't put on airs!
This dump needs all the clients
it can get.
Bastard!
Easy, Shinkichi!
You can listen and bet
at the same time.
Calling me by my first name?
That's no way to speak to a client!
A client?
You used to work for me.
Shut up and bet!
You asked for it.
The last sound was...
OK...
Odd!
Odd.
Game.
4 and 2, even!
So?
A message for your boss...
What?
Drop dead!
Is Mrs. Izutsu in?
One moment, please.
May I ask
what business you have here?
Your dead husband has gambling debts
to my establishment.
I'm taking your store.
You have three days to vacate.
Not one day more.
This is madness!
Shut up!
Don't interfere!
See those beauties?
- Know them?
- Nope.
I wish! The one in red is hot.
More sake, please.
Osei...
Should we ask around for work?
Sir...
Do you know a place
where we could offer our services?
Business has been slow
and we're available.
Do you know of anyone?
You should try Mr. Ogi.
He runs everything now,
thanks to Ginzo.
This Mr. Ogi...
Can you introduce us to him?
Pops, give those ladies a hand.
Gramps, go and see Ogi.
Go yourself, bastard!
Stop exploiting the old man!
Hurry up!
Presenting the windmill!
Watch it turn!
Boss!
The tavern owner recommends
two geishas.
They're available this evening.
Excellent. Send them over!
You two, beat it!
Lord Sakai, we'll soon be
in the company of two gorgeous women.
Hurry up.
What's next?
Even.
Even!
Bets are placed.
Game.
3 and 5, even.
A winner!
Ogi!
Must I watch this much longer?
Let's have some dancing!
Show's over! Beat it!
Time to dance, girls!
Hurry up! Dance!
Odd.
Bets are placed.
Game.
4 and 1, odd.
Masseur, should we bet it all?
New game.
Objections?
Hey!
The dice don't sound the same.
Damned masseur!
Master...
Some masseur is tearing up
the gambling house.
Boss wants you to go there.
A masseur?
Please, sir.
You're coming with me.
Let me go.
Come on.
Do as he says!
Don't touch me!
You OK?
Watch your step.
Ouch!
Be careful!
What are you looking at?
Masseur...
Wait here.
I’ll see what's happening.
Ouch!
Ladies, this way.
Hurry!
That Ogi is a horrible man!
I hit him and we took off
when the client tried to take Osei.
We ran into trouble at Ginzo's place.
But the masseur floored them all.
It was unbelievable.
Who are you, anyway?
They'll track us down here soon.
We should go to my aunt's house.
Impossible.
Ginzo's men are everywhere.
That's true.
I have an idea.
Okinu, do you have some make-up?
Sure.
Masseur, come here.
Don't move.
- What's that?
- I'm drawing eyes.
Eyes for me?
Open up!
Who could it be at this hour?
Who is it?
Your nephew Shinkichi.
Shinkichi?
He must have lost everything again.
Come in.
Who are these people?
Careful, Masseur.
- Masseur!
- Yes, it's me.
Useless fools!
What about the bodyguard?
It was all over by the time he arrived.
The masseur had already run off.
Who is this masseur?
Don't know. Just some masseur.
He had that punk Shinkichi with him.
He's a regular at the joint.
He shouldn't be difficult to find.
As for the masseur, we'll get him.
First, we must wipe out
the Funahachi gang.
It can't be...
We found ourselves traveling
from town to town...
Tricking men and stealing their money.
10 years of that?
Those bandits must be living
different lives by now.
Wait...
Didn't Ogi settle here 10 years ago?
That's right.
In fact, that Ogi...
There's something not right about him.
I saw his arm.
He has a snake tattoo.
Wait a minute...
Those names you mentioned...
Something about a Kuchinawa?
Yes, that's right.
Kuchinawa means "rotten rope"...
That could mean a snake.
Right?
Masseur!
Don't make those eyes at me!
I heard about last night...
A masseur tore up your place.
That's right.
We rushed over with the bodyguard.
But we got there too late.
Ogi...
What were the women like?
Lord Sakai tried to carry one away.
But the other one hit me real hard.
Based on their moves...
They're no ordinary geishas.
Listen...
Find out everything you can
about that masseur and those geishas.